Fanzine Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Fanzine Collection.
undated, 1945-1985.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Unknown.
16.25 linear feet.
MSS20010012
History
Unknown.
Scope and Content
United States and Western European fanzines, primarily science fiction and fantasy.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of alternative and underground publications. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Fanzines.; Science fiction—History and criticism—Periodicals.; Popular culture—Periodicals.; Underground press publications.; Periodicals—Specimens.; Fanzines—Specimens.; Fantasy fiction, American—Periodicals.; Fantasy fiction, American—Periodicals—Specimens.; Fanzines—Periodicals.; Fantasy literature—European—Periodicals.
Document Types:
Publications.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from collector.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, 1945-1985
  - Amateur Offerings. Roanoke, VA.
    - 1974 December (Othertype #13)
    - 1969 September - 1970 February (Othertype #20-22)
    - 1971 October (Othertype #25)
    - 1977 January (Othertype #27)
  - American Evangelist and Ajayer. Salem, VA.
    - 1969 Winter - 1970 June (Volume Volume 5:, Othertype #2-3)
  - Anomaly. New Haven, CT.
    - 1975 April (Othertype #2)
  - Antares: Bilim Kurgu. (Science Fiction) Ankara, Turkey.
    - 1974 March (Othertype #1)
  - Arena Science Fiction. Birchington, Kent, England.
    - 1980 April (Othertype #10)
    - 1981 Sumer (Othertype #12)
  - Asgard. Stockholm, Sweden.
    - 1970 October (Othertype #2)
  - Atheism and Free Love. Hastings, MN.
    - 1970 May - September (Othertype #23-24)
  - Awry. Duarte, CA.
    - 1976 January (Othertype #10)
  - Banshee. Waterford, CT
    - 1974 January - 1974 August (Othertype #6-#9)
  - Batrachomyomachia. Carlton South, Victoria, Australia.
    - 1972 (?) August (Othertype #1)
  - Beardmutterings. Washington, D.C.
    - 1983 March (Othertype #4)
  - Best Lines are on the Floor (A Genuine FAPA One-shot). La Mirada, CA.
    - 1975 July
    - 1975 October
    - 1976 February
  - Boonfark. Falls Church, VA.
    - 1983 Spring (Othertype #8)
  - Burblings. Garden Grove, CA.
    - 1985February
  - Busted Flush. Milford, CT.
    - 1973 (Othertype #1)
  - Celephais. Rockville, MI.
    - 1973 February
  - Cepheid. Brooklyn, NY.
    - 1946 Spring (Volume Volume 1:, Othertype #2)
  - Chao. Havelock, Vict., Australia.
    - [1 issue?]
  - Chicago Fantasy Newsletter.
    - 1980 June/July (Othertype #11)
  - Collector's Bulletin. Newport News, VA.
    - 1966 March (Othertype #4)
  - Contest News. Roanoke, VA.
    - 1970 November (Othertype #19)
    - 1971 March (Othertype #23)
  - Crabapple Gazette. Tangent, OR.
    - 1968 April (Volume Volume 1:, Othertype #1)
  - Crank. Falls Church, VA.
    - 1985 September - October (Othertype #1-2)
  - Cygnus X-1. Pittsburgh, PA.
    - [1975]
  - Desk Set Gazette. Falls Church, VA.
    - 1985 November (Othertype #2)
  - Diehard. Wickliffe, OH.
    - 1973 (Othertype #1-2)
  - Dionysos. Goteborg, Sweden.
    - 1969 January (Othertype #5)
  - Double bill. Akron, OH.
    - [1 issue?]
  - Dreams and False Alarms. Melbourne, Australia.
    - 1984 August (Othertype #1)
  - Driftglass. Kolbotn, Norway.
    - 1975 (Othertype #24)
  - Duff (Down Under Fan Fund). Bass Hill, NSW, Australia.
    - 1974
    - 1975
    - Newsletter 4-5
  - Dynatron. Albuquerque, NM.
    - 1972 May (Othertype #49)
    - 1973 October - November (Othertype #55-56)
    - 1974 September - 1975 November (Othertype #60-64)
    - 1981 February (Othertype #74)
    - 1984 February (Othertype #80)
    - 1984 November - 1985 May (Othertype #82-83)
  - ECCE: Extrapolation Causes Concerned Excitement. Platteville, WI.
    - undated, 1973 Spring (Volume Volume 1:, Othertype #1, Volume Volume 2:, Othertype #2 (no. 3))
  - Edward Wood's Checklist to Fantastic Universe. N.P.
    - Lore Supplement, 1966 (Othertype #1)
  - Empire for the SF Writer. New Haven, CT.
    - 1982 Winter (Othertype #30)
  - Enceladus. Arnold, MO.
    - 1975 (?) (Othertype #5)
  - ERB-dom. Evergreen, CO.
    - [1 issue?]
  - ERG. Sheffield, England.
    - 1973 July (Othertype #43)
    - 1985 April (Othertype #90)
  - Etcetera and the Comic Reader. Brooklyn, NY.
    - 1977 December (Othertype #10/77)
  - Fantasy Rotator. Covina, CA.
    - 1965 September 13 (Othertype #168)
  - Fanzine Fantastique. Lancaster, England.
    - 1975 May (Othertype #8)
  - Feemwlort. San Bruno, CA.
    - 1965 August (Othertype #3)
  - First Draft. Kingston, Australia.
    - 1975 January (Othertype #1)
  - FPO (For Paranoids Only). Leeds, England.
    - 1985 April - August (Othertype #6-7)
  - From Sunday to Saturday. Covina, CA.
    - 1973 February
  - Gore Creatures. Baltimore, MD.
    - 1970 August (Othertype #18)
    - 1971 September (Othertype #20)
  - Gran Delusions. Dearborn, MI.
    - [1978 December ?] (Othertype #1)
  - Grandfather Stories. Dearborn, MI.
    - (1973 February)
  - Granfalloon. Prospect Park, PA.
    - 1974 December (Othertype #19:, Volume Volume 7,, Othertype #1)
  - The Grape Vine. Roanoke, VA.
    - 1985 July (Othertype #31)
  - The Grimling Bosch. Gateshead, England.
    - 1973 July (Othertype #6)
  - Guying Gyre. Torrence, CA. Gilbert Gaier.
    - 1974 Fall - Winter (Othertype #1-2)
  - Hampton Roads Review. Newport News, VA.
    - 1966 August - October
  - Harbinger 5. Sandy, UT.
    - [1 issue?]
  - Haverings. Surbiton, Surrey, England.
    - 1971 July/August - December (Othertype #50-51)
    - 1973 January (Othertype #54)
    - 1974 November (Othertype #58)
  - Hell. Manchester, England.
    - 1973 October - 1974 May (Othertype #9-10)
  - The High Asthetic Line. Costa Mesa, CA. D. Hulan.
    - [1976?] (Othertype #13)
  - Holland-SF. Hilversum, Holland.
    - undated (Volume Volume 2:, Othertype #6)
    - 1969 (Volume Volume 3:, Othertype #2)
    - 1971 February - April (Volume Volume 5:, Othertype #1-2)
  - Interfandom. London, England.
    - 1970 May
  - Inworlds. Wadsworth, OH.
    - 1973 August - 1974 March/April (Othertype #9-11)
  - Joy. Stockport, Cheshire, England.
    - 1973 July (Othertype #2)
  - Karass. Prospect Park, PA.
    - 1974 February - September (Othertype #2-7)
    - 1975 January (Othertype #10-11)
    - 1975 June - September (Othertype #15-17)
  - Kim Chi. Oakland, CA.
    - undated (Othertype #14)
  - King Kon. Stockport, Lancastershire, England.
    - Unnumbered, {1972?]
  - Knockers from Neptune. Derby, England.
    - 1975 July - 1976 February (Othertype #1-3)
  - Letters from Leng. Storrs, CT: R.M. Eber.
    - {1 issue?]
  - The Lion Roars. Peru, IL.
    - 1974 June (Volume Volume 3:, Othertype #6)
    - Interchange track, 1974 September 1
  - Literary Newsletter. Roanoke, VA.
    - 1974 October/November (Othertype #585-587)
    - 1977 January - February (Othertype #595-597)
    - 1985 July (Othertype #683)
  - Loki. Costa Mesa, CA.
    - 1976 September (Othertype #13)
  - London SF. London, England.
    - 1977 Autumn (Othertype #1)
  - Lurk. Derby, England: P. and M. Meara
    - (Othertype #1-#7)
  - Madcap. Stockport, England.
    - undated, 1972 >November/December (Othertype #2-3)
  - Malfunction. Stockport, England.
    - [1973?] (Othertype #3)
  - Maule's Well. Newcastle upon Tyne, England.
    - 1972 December 3 (Othertype #7)
  - Maya. Newcastle upon Tyne, England.
    - 1975 November - 1976 March (Othertype #9-10)
  - The Mentor. Barberton, OH.
    - 1972 Autumn (Othertype #22)
  - Metanoia. Burbank, CA.
    - 1973 February (Othertype #13)
  - Metaphysical Review. Melbourne, Australia.
    - 1984 November - 1985 July (Othertype #2-4)
  - National Fantasy Fan. See TNFF (The National Fantasy Fan).
  - The Nehwon Review. Berkeley, CA.
    - 1970/71 Winter (Othertype #7)
  - New libertarian notes. New York.
    - [1 issue?]
  - Nickoloeon.
    - [1 issue?]
  - Nostalgia News. Dallas, TX.
    - 1972 (Othertype #14)
  - Notiziario CCSF. Venice, Italy.
    - 1968 Maggio (Othertype #4)
  - Outworlds. Wadsworth, OH.
    - 1973 June - October (Othertype #16-18)
    - 1974 (Othertype #21-22)
  - Pelf. Costa Mesa, CA.
    - 1977 May (Othertype #13)
  - Pendulum Blimp. Normanhurst, Australia.
    - 1973 April 17 (Othertype #2)
  - People Watcher. Iowa, City, IA.
    - 1977 February (Othertype #51)
  - Personal Notes. Cambridge, MA.
    - 1974 August 13 - 1976 February 9 (Othertype #1-6)
  - Philosophical Gas. Kingston, Australia.
    - 1974 Autumn - 1975 March (Othertype #27-30)
  - Photron. Ames, IA.
    - 1974 October (Othertype #12)
    - 1979 September (Othertype #16)
  - The Poet's Glass Eye. DeSoto, TX.
    - 1976 November (Othertype #1)
  - Poor Richard's Adzine. Chicago, IL.
    - 1974 (Othertype #1)
  - Quasar Reviews. Lake Buena Vista, FL.
    - 1982 September/October - 1983 January/February (Othertype #7-9)
  - Quinnapolus. Minneapolis, MN.
    - 1979 December - 1981 January (Othertype #4-5)
  - Rataplan. Balaclava, Victoria, Australia.
    - [1972 Fall?] (Othertype #10)
    - 1974 May (Othertype #16)
  - Requiem. Longueuil, Quebec.
    - 1974 (Volume Volume 1:, Othertype #2)
  - Revival. Locust Grove, OK.
    - One shot, (1975 March)
  - Rhetorical Device. Seattle, WA.
    - 1984 April (Othertype #3)
  - Rigel Science Fiction. Richmond, CA.
    - 1981 Summer (Othertype #1)
  - Robert Bloch Fanzine. Los Altos, CA.
    - Second edition 1973 September.
  - Rot. North Yorkshire, England.
    - 1984 Autumn (Othertype #6)
  - Sam. Baltimore, MD.
    - 1983 Spring (Othertype #15)
  - Science Fiction Digest Quarterly. Cheshire, England.
    - (Othertype #17-19)
    - [1979-1984?] (Othertype #21-24)
  - Science Fiction Review. Santa Monica, CA.
    - 1969 April (Othertype #30)
  - Science Fiction Times. Syracuse, NY.
    - [1967? September]
  - Science Fiction Times: Informationen uber Spekulative und Phantastische Literatur. Bremerhavn, Germany.
    - 1969 February - March (Othertype #92-93)
    - 1969 August (Othertype #99)
  - Scottishe. Surbiton, Surrey, England.
    - undated (Othertype #61)
    - 1974 September - 1975 October (Othertype #68-70)
    - 1980 December (Othertype #80)
  - Seldon's Plan. Detroit, MI.
    - 1974 - 1974 June (Volume Volume 6:, Othertype #2-3)
  - SF Commentary. Melbourne, Australia.
    - 1973 Mary (Othertype #34)
    - 1974 September (Othertype #38)
    - 1974 May - 1975 February (Othertype #40-41/42)
    - 1975 December (Othertype #44/45)
    - 1979 November (Othertype #57)
    - 1980 April (Othertype #59)
  - Shambles. Locust Grove, OK/Duarte, CA.
    - 1975 June - 1976 February (Othertype #1-2)
  - Shangri-L'Affaires. Los Angeles, CA.
    - 1946 May (Othertype #30)
  - The Showcase. Roanoke, VA.
    - 1971 February - March (Othertype #50-51)
    - 1985 January - February (Othertype #101-102)
    - 1985 April - June (Othertype #104-106)
  - Siddhartha. Sunderland, Durham, England.
    - 1972 (Othertype #1)
  - Snap. Kew Gardens, NY.
    - 1973 Spring (Othertype #1)
  - Son of the WSFA Journal. Wheaton, MD.
    - 1973 April (Othertype #87)
  - Space & Time. New York, NY.
    - 1981 January (Othertype #58)
  - Speculation.
    - 1972 Autumn (Othertype #31)
  - Starship Tripe. All published continued by Banshee.
    - 1973 July (Othertype #1)
    - 1973 August - October (Othertype #4-5)
  - Tabebuian. Miami, FL.
    - 1974 January - April (Othertype #9-12)
    - 1974 September (Othertype #15)
    - 1975 January (Othertype #17)
  - Tandstikkerzeitung. New Orleans, LA.
    - 1974 June - 1975 October (Othertype #6-9)
  - Tellus. Alter Kirchhainer, Germany.
    - 1972 August 22 (Othertype #3)
  - Till the Cows Come Home. Franfurt am Main, Germany.
    - 1974 July - October (Othertype #2-3)
  - Timebeam. Goteborg, Sweden.
    - 1969 (Othertype #1)
  - TNFF (The National Fantasy Fan). Albuquerque, NM.
    - 1980 (Volume Volume 40:, Othertype #2)
  - Transplant. St. Albans, Hertfordshire, England.
    - 1969 September
  - Trap Door. Glen Ellen, CA.
    - 1983 October - 1985 May (Othertype #1-4)
  - Trill. Cleveland, OH.
    - 1973 February
  - Trove. Vallejo, CA.
    - undated (Othertype #1)
  - Tucker Bag. Beecher, IL.
    - 1974 June/July (Othertype #2)
  - Twilightzine. Cambridge, MA.
    - 1980 January (Othertype #33)
    - 1983 September (Othertype #35)
  - Twonk's Disease. Gateshead, Durham, England.
    - 1974 January (Othertype #1)
  - Viewpoint. Baltimore, MD.
    - 1973 February (Othertype #1)
  - Warhoon. Old San Juan, Puerto Rico.
    - 1981 October (Othertype #29)
  - Whistlestar. San Francisco, CA.
    - 1984 June (Othertype #1)
  - Wiz. San Juan, Puerto Rico.
    - 1983 December 12 (Othertype #8)
  - Yandro. Hartford City, IN.
    - 1974 September - 1976 April (Othertype #228-235)
    - 1979 August/September - 1980 January (Othertype #247/248-249)
    - 1981 February (Othertype #252)
    - 1982 March (Othertype #255)
  - Yezidee. Los Angeles, CA.
    - 1963 March 9 (Othertype #3)
  - Zimri. Manchester, England.
    - 1973 January-August (includes #4 ½) (Othertype #4-5)
    - 1976 March/April (Othertype #8)
  - Le Zombie. Jacksonville, IL.
    - 1975 December (Othertype #67)